<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Gazoo.cpp</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/</link>
<description>An independent developer in the wild</description>
<language>en-uk</language>
<item>
<title>Hello!</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-06-06-20-20-57</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-06-06-20-20-57</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 20:20:57 +0100</pubDate>
<description>Welcome to my blog :)

In the next couple of weeks I'll be starting my own business in Brighton and couldn't be more excited about it! At the moment, I'm taking a little holiday so my days consist of catching up on sleep, cooking, gardening</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Office Space +1</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-06-09-23-55-57</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-06-09-23-55-57</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 23:55:57 +0100</pubDate>
<description>Today I managed to get some office space locked down! It's right in the middle of Brighton Laines above a book shop - I have a single room and share the building with several other small businesses (including the guy who invented an</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Gubberment and the new PC</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-06-14-15-23-56</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-06-14-15-23-56</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 15:23:56 +0100</pubDate>
<description>I move into the office next Monday - meanwhile I've been keeping myself busy trawling through government websites on the requirements of being self-employed. As a result; I'm going to contact an accountant as soon as po</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Build System DIY</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-06-28-17-04-00</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-06-28-17-04-00</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 17:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
<description>UPDATE: The source code to PiB is {now available|PiB}.

I've been setup in the new office now for a good 5 days and there have been bits of progress made here and there. Monday last week involved me building my new desk, cleaning </description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Compile-time logarithms in C++</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-07-12-16-58-49</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-07-12-16-58-49</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 16:58:49 +0100</pubDate>
<description>Just thought I'd record a quick bit of code that's come in handy just now. Maybe when I get used to this blog thing I'll do this more frequently!

I was writing a 64-bit itoa and needed to figure out how many bytes a</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Variadic macro dispatch in Visual C++ 2005 and later</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-07-15-10-23-25</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-07-15-10-23-25</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 10:23:25 +0100</pubDate>
<description>While the world awaits the arrival of variadic macros in C++, most production compilers out there have added [lit]__VA_ARGS__[/lit] support as an extension with implementations that vary quite sub</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lightweight Javascript Blogging</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-08-16-17-27-23</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-08-16-17-27-23</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 17:27:23 +0100</pubDate>
<description>My blog has been a bit quiet for a while and I assure you that it will become apparent why within the week :) I'm hoping to also share a few words on what it feels like to be self-employed for a couple of months now.</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introducing clReflect - C++ Reflection with clang</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-08-17-14-36-04</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-08-17-14-36-04</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2011 14:36:04 +0100</pubDate>
<description>Over the last few weeks I've been working, advisable or not, on what I think is a pretty reliable way of generating and using Reflection information for programs written in C++. The result is {clRefl</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>The life of a self-employed</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-09-08-21-41-00</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-09-08-21-41-00</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 21:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
<description>So I'm at the 3 month mark of being self-employed and everything is going good. It's about time I broke the trend of technical posts and covered some real life news.

As far as project progress is concerned, I'm not whe</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>clReflect 0.3 released</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-11-29-11-18-30</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-11-29-11-18-30</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 11:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
<description>After a couple months hard work, the latest version of clReflect has been uploaded; you can download it {here|https://bitbucket.org/dwilliamson/clreflect/downloads/clReflect-0.3.7z} or browse the latest source code {here|https</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>The UK: Credit is King and the self-employed live outside the castle walls</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-12-15-13-02-00</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2011-12-15-13-02-00</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description>I figured I'd cover a bit about what's been going on behind the scenes lately while I try to build my game. It's a bit personal but I suppose it can be considered a "human in</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>A New Year (monster) update</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-01-16-22-26-00</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-01-16-22-26-00</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 22:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description>I'm writing this post from the comfort of my very large sofa, under a dimmed lamp, while {QI|http://www.qi.com/tv/} plays amusingly on the TV in the background. We finally managed to find a nice house to rent and have slo</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>An RPC Debugging Workflow with Visual Studio</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-02-07-11-37-23</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-02-07-11-37-23</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 11:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
<description>I love {Sublime Text 2|http://www.sublimetext.com/2}. For me, it does nearly everything a modern C++ code editing platform should do and is constantly moving in a direction that is pleasing to the soul. I</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cross-browser, Native/Remote D3D Rendering with C++</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-03-08-13-00-00</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-03-08-13-00-00</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2012 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<description>As my little game project builds steam and I become more confident that it will actually work, it's becoming easier for me to talk about the various problems I've had to tackle.

A little backg</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Risk, Prototypes and Planetary Bodies</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-04-11-22-56-23</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-04-11-22-56-23</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 22:56:23 +0100</pubDate>
<description>Last month quietly welcomed the completion of my game/platform prototype: 8 months in the making! I'm only a few months away from an announcement for what I'm working on but it's worth taking a step back and loo</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>An Implementation of _CIpow</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-05-15-10-36-23</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-05-15-10-36-23</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 10:36:23 +0100</pubDate>
<description>The game I'm working on is playable in a browser and written in C++. There are no installation steps: you just head to the webpage, it syncs the latest version and you play. To achieve this I had to build my own C/C++ CRT</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Quaternions and Dual Quaternion Skinning</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-07-19-12-52-03</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-07-19-12-52-03</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 12:52:03 +0100</pubDate>
<description>For some reason I like quaternions. I fell in love with complex numbers back in school when I found out that they {made more sense than real numbers|http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algebraically_closed_field#E</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Getting Google to Index AJAX Content</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-07-27-12-42-30</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-07-27-12-42-30</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 12:42:30 +0100</pubDate>
<description>I'm stuck on quite a major feature and only have a few hours of time available to work today so I thought I'd take a break and work on something that has been confusing me for a while, now.

I use {TinyBlog|T</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Smoother Assert Response with Visual Studio</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-08-02-18-01-22</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-08-02-18-01-22</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 18:01:22 +0100</pubDate>
<description>In my never-ending crusade to make my programming life as easy as possible, reducing click counts and milliseconds between iteration, I came up with a quick hack to my setup that speeds up my assert resp</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Skeletal Animation Looping with Autocorrelation</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-08-20-16-07-23</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-08-20-16-07-23</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 16:07:23 +0100</pubDate>
<description>This is a bit of a fun post highlighting how some simple maths can be used to create great visual results. With some basic statistics, we can create looping skeletal animations from an input data set</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Announcing Project: Star</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-11-07-17-10-02</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-11-07-17-10-02</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 17:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
<description>It's about time I started talking about my new game. I want to keep things very low-key for the moment so I'll limit activity to this blog until I have more to show. Over the coming months, starting with the first screenshot</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scale, Physics and Shading</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-11-15-12-43-24</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-11-15-12-43-24</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 12:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
<description>My goal for this project is to run in a browser with no installation steps required. This means I can't rely on any software on the host machine that needs to be installed by hand. I also wanted the executables to be as sm</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Native Browser Games &amp; Tools with clReflect</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-11-22-13-08-40</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-11-22-13-08-40</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 13:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
<description>A long time passed between development of the previous screenshots and the ones I'll show here; I think it was about a month or so. A quick summary of the additions would be:

* The game is now hosted in</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Record/Playback and a New Window Manager</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-11-30-12-30-01</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-11-30-12-30-01</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 12:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
<description>Before we head into December, I figured I'd show you some screenshots from the progress I made prior to the scope of this all going a bit crazy :)

Here's a quick shot of the Editing Room at that point:

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Distance Fields to Voxels to Polygons</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-12-06-10-34-03</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-12-06-10-34-03</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 10:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
<description>At this point things were looking pretty good: I setup a few car chases and did some bullet-proofing of clip composition for movies. The next stage was to figure out how the world would look and stream/generate </description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Planets, Smooth Voxels and Runtime C++ Reloading</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-12-12-19-20-54</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-12-12-19-20-54</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 19:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
<description>In a previous post I hinted at my next decision: is the game set on an island? I think from the title of this post, you can guess that it isn't :)

== Let's Render Planets! ==

The noise generatio</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Very Fast, High-Precision SIMD/GPU Gradient Noise</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-12-17-11-38-22</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-12-17-11-38-22</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 11:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
<description>A recently published article by Inigo Quilez on {Voronoi Edges|http://www.iquilezles.org/www/articles/voronoilines/voronoilines.htm} highlights the technique of shifting the co-ordinate frame of proc</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Transvoxel Level of Detail and Collision</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-12-20-14-42-56</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2012-12-20-14-42-56</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 14:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
<description>For some reason my brain went into overdrive when handling the gaps between LOD levels - no gap was too small to need a fix. In retrospect, maybe moving back to restore the gameplay code as soon as voxels wer</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Space Colonies with Simple Maths</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2013-01-07-16-41-34</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2013-01-07-16-41-34</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 16:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
<description>During one of my sleepless nights I was going over all the benefits and drawbacks of distance functions and my mind wandered onto their flexibility. Given that the base distance function is just the distance from the</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kinect Acting with IK and a New DirectX 11 Renderer</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2013-01-18-11-52-29</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2013-01-18-11-52-29</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 11:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
<description>I think we're about up to the middle of last year in these posts and at this point I was feeling a little too confident: I'd cracked the voxel nut and was well on my way to larger worlds. What next</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Earth-size Voxel Planets with Atmospheric Scattering</title>
<link>http://donw.org/b/?d=2013-01-22-08-09-43</link>
<guid>http://donw.org/b/?d=2013-01-22-08-09-43</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 08:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
<description>After 3 months of exhaustive Kinect/IK work, I needed a little motivation boost so I tackled two problems: making much bigger worlds with massive draw distances and putting a pretty atmosphere aro</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
